Preliminary Inventory to the Leland T. Chapin Papers, 1941-1944
Hoover Institution Archives
Leland T. Chapin Papers,
1941-1944
69025
Chapin, Leland T.
1 manuscript box (0.4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Writings, minutes of meetings, radio transcripts, and serial issues, relating to the promotion of patriotism in Hawaiian schools and within the Oriental community in Hawaii, and to military government in the Marshall Islands during World War II.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Access Points
Asians--Hawaii; Education; Military government; World War, 1939-1945; World War, 1939-1945--Education and the war; World War, 1939-1945--Hawaii; World War, 1939-1945--Marshall Islands; World War, 1939-1945--United States; Hawaii; Marshall Islands; United States--Armed Forces
Container List
- Correspondence with University of Hawaii, Punahou School, etc.; Radio Station Transcript KGMP, 1942 January-May (Box 1.)
- Military publications
  - "The Rip Cord," vol. 2, no. 12, 1941 September 19
  - "Hickam Highlights," vol. 5, nos. 14-15, 1941 October
  - "Truck Tracks," Fort Wayne, Detroit, Mich., vol. 1, no. 8
  - "Chanute Field Wings," no. 19, 1941 September 26
- Hawaiian newspapers
  - The Kauai Shinpo, no. 1874, 1941 November
  - The Garden Island, vol. 38, no. 44, 1941 November
  - The Hawaii Mainichi, vol. 35, nos. 9123-9124, 1941 December
  - The Maui Record, vol. 24, nos. 2408-2409, 1941 December 9
  - The Kwazan, English and Japanese newspaper, 1941 December
  - The Valley Isle Chronicle, Wailuku, Maui, Hawaii, 1941 December-1942 January
  - Hawaii Chinese Journal, vol. 5, nos. 45, 48, 1941 November 13, December 4
  - Ka Leo O Hawaii, vol. 20, nos. 2, 3 (2x), 1941 September 17, November (University of Hawaii publications)
  - The Herald, Honolulu, vol. II, nos. 12-16, 1941; vol. III, nos. 1-4, 1942
  - The Sentinel, vol. 7, nos. 28, 31-32, 1941 November 13, December 4, 11 (Hawaii's American newspaper)
  - The Korean National Herald - Pacific Weekly, vol. 1, nos. 3, 11, 1942 February, April